So, this exercise asked us to use this list of colors to draw a rainbow shape.
所以 这项运动要求我们用这个颜色列表画出彩虹的形状
In this video, I'm going to show how to make
在这个视频中 我将展示如何制作
a hexagon where each side is a different color.
一个六边形 每个边都是不同的颜色
Since there are six sides and a hexagon and six colors in this list,
既然这里有六面六色
there will be one color for each side.
每边都有一个颜色
The first thing we need to do is add code to create a new turtle.
我们首先需要做的是添加代码来创建新的海龟
Then we can write the code to draw a hexagon.
然后我们可以写代码来绘制一个六边形
Now, we already have done something like that from
我们已经做过类似的事了
an earlier lesson but we just haven't made it rainbow-colored yet.
但我们还没有把它做成彩虹色
When I'm experimenting with something new and I'm not quite sure how to do it,
当我尝试新事物时 我不太确定如何去做
I'll often start with whatever parts I know pretty well how to do and
我常常会从我最熟悉的地方开始
then work step-by-step from there toward what the new thing is.
然后从那里一步步走向新事物
So for now, I'm not going to worry about the rainbow part.
所以现在 我不会去担心彩虹部分
I'm just going to start by drawing a simple hexagon.
我只是从一个简单的六边形开始
To do that, I'm going to use a for loop.
要做到这一点 我要用一个 for 循环
Since the hexagon has six sides,
既然六边形有六个侧面
I'll have the loop run six times.
我将会有六次循环
I can do that by using a list with six items like this.
我可以用一个包含 6 个项目的列表来做到这一点
Each time the loop runs,
每次循环运行时
I'll have the turtle go forward by
我会让乌龟前进
100 pixels which will be one of the sides of the hexagon.
100 个像素 将是六边形的侧面之一
Then it needs to turn.
然后它需要转动
As we saw earlier,
正如我们刚才看到的
we can get the turning angle for any regular polygon by dividing
我们可以通过划分来获取任何正多边形的转角
360 degrees by however many sides the shape has.
但其形状有360 度
Three hundred and sixty divided by six is 60
360 除以 6 是 60
so I'll have the turtle turn right by 60 degrees.
我会让海龟右转 60 度
So, at this point we should have functioning code that draws a hexagon.
所以 在这一点上 我们应该有一个可以使用六边形的功能代码
Whenever I get to a point in my code where I
每当我在我的代码中找到一个点
think it should run and have some visible results,
认为它应该运行并产生一些可见的结果
I like to test it to make sure it's working how I expect.
我喜欢测试它以确保它的工作方式
That way I could catch any little errors that I might have made while I was working,
这样我就能发现我在工作时可能犯的小错误
and yeah, it looks like it's drawing a hexagon.
好像是在画一个六边形
It's so little hard to see because it's using such a thin black line.
因为它用了这么薄的黑色线条 所以很难看
So one little thing I can change,
我可以改变一点
is make the line thicker using the width method.
使线条更厚 使用宽度方法
Now we need to think about changing the color.
现在我们需要考虑改变颜色
First, I'll start by just setting a single color like we've done before.
首先 我先设定一个像以前一样的颜色
I also don't particularly like the hexagon's off-center.
我也不特别喜欢六边形的离中心
It's kind of down off to the right.
从右到右
So, I'm going to have the turtle back up a little before it starts drawing.
所以 我要让海龟在开始画画前稍微恢复一点
I now hide the turtle when it's done drawing just so that
我现在把乌龟藏起来
we don't have a little arrowhead shape sticking out of our shape.
我们没有一个小小的箭头形状
So now we need to think about how to get it to
所以现在我们要想想怎么弄
change its color every time it runs through the loop,
每次都改变它的颜色
and we know that we want to use this list of colors here.
我们知道我们想用这里的颜色列表
More specifically, we need to use a different one of
更确切地说 我们需要使用不同的
the colors in this list every time the loop runs through.
每次循环运行时 此列表中的颜色
The trick here is to use the loop variable.
这里的诀窍是使用循环变量
Right now we have a loop variable named side,
现在我们有一个循环变量
and each time the loop runs,
每次循环运行
this variable gets assigned a number from this list.
此变量将从该列表中指定一个编号
One through six.
一到六
But we're not doing anything with these numbers.
但我们没有对这些数字做任何事情
We're just using the fact that there are six of them.
我们只是用了其中的六个
However, this rainbow list also has six items in it.
不过 这个彩虹名单里面还有 6 个项目
So, we could replace our list of numbers with that list of colors,
所以我们可以用那个颜色列表来替换我们的号码
and our program shouldn't really do what it's doing.
我们的节目不该这么做
It should still draw a hexagon just like before.
它还应该像以前一样画一个六边形
Now, since each of the items in this list is a color,
既然这个清单里的每一项都是一种颜色
I'm going to change the name of the variable from side to pretty color.
我要将变量的名称从侧面更改为漂亮的颜色
I called it pretty color rather than just color because I
我把它叫做颜色 而不是颜色 因为我
didn't want to confuse it with the color method.
不想把它和颜色的方法混为一谈
Now each time the loop runs,
每次循环运行
the pretty color variable will be getting a different color from the list.
美丽的颜色变量将从列表中获取不同的颜色
First red then orange then yellow and so on.
先是红色 然后是橙色 然后是黄色等等
But we're still not doing anything with these colors.
但我们仍然没有用这些颜色做任何事情
So when we run the code,
所以当我们运行代码时
we just get a plane red hexagon and all we need to
我们只需要一个正六边形的飞机
do is to set the color based on that pretty color variable.
根据该颜色变量设置颜色
So now each time the loop runs,
每次循环运行
we're passing a different color to
我们把不同的颜色传递给
the color method which is then used for one of the sides,
颜色的方法 然后用在一个侧面上
and there we go.
然后就开始了
A rainbow hexagon.
一个彩虹六边形